Music and culture and art are forms of nurturing and strengthening us to continue to do what we need to do.
And so it's like a symbiotic relationship, right?
Like the movement feeds the artist, but the artist also in many ways feeds the movement.
So I appreciate it.
I remember being at the Martin Luther King Center with you in Cuba and asking, like, how does art factor into the work you're doing here?
And they were saying exactly that.
I was very honored and privileged to go with a whole bunch of amazing people in March.
And you were militantly one of those amazing people in that delegation.
You know, everything from getting to the airport and being hit with, you cannot bring as many bags.
I mean, mind you, these were bags filled with medicine, like necessary medicine.
Some of these were, you know, vials of medicine for cancer patients, like to that extent.
And we were being told by the airline, well, you cannot bring this amount.
And so we had to immediately go on reorganizing mode.
And it's so crazy also just to see the solidarity that workers will show.
You remember a sister from Jamaica.
Listen, at first she was giving, I'm the boss, and I said that they weren't going on the plane, so they're not going on the plane.
And y'all, when she realized, oh, because we start opening up the bags.
And, you know, I think they may have thought we were boosters.
Yeah.
And that we were going down there with purses.
You know what I'm saying?
And it's like, no, we start opening up the bags, and it's vitamins.
And like you said, it's vials of medication, et cetera.
And then her whole energy switch up.
And next thing you know, she's like, you know, they shouldn't have taken the doctors from Cuba.
I mean, from Jamaica.
The Cuban doctors have been so helpful to Jamaica.
Yeah.
Exactly.
I was really happy to see that turn around and to see her, you know, really just do everything in her power.
Because that's the thing, is that that's what solidarity ends up really being about, using everything in your power.
So it's not poor Cuba.
We're doing this because we acknowledge that Cuba is an extension of us as working people.
And we are an extension of Cuba.
And that we are more connected to each other than we could possibly ever be to the Trumps and the Bidens and the Kamalas of the world.
Like, we have more in common with regular working class people that are struggling to survive under the condition of a slow genocide that is being imposed on them than we do with, like, any of the so-called leaders of this country.
I needed that.
I didn't know how much I needed that.
Thank you.
I can't wait to hear the album.